Frank Morigi Papers
Frank Morigi Papers
1968-2004
Morigi, Francis C.
3.25 linear ft.
American interior/industrial designer and Syracuse University professor. Collection includes articles, clippings, photographs, working drawings, specifications, student work and other items relating to educational, hotel/restaurant, office space, retail and historical preservation projects.
3314277
Biographical History
Frank Morigi is an American interior design consultant and educator. He began his career in 1965 in Chicago with the firm of Norman R. DeHaan Associates, for whom he designed interiors for stores, restaurants, exhibit spaces and offices throughout the United States and Canada. He has taught at Southern Illinois University and at Syracuse University, where he was Professor of Interior Design and Chair of the Department of Design. Research projects, many of which involved his students, have included design studies for Haworth, the Juvenile Products Manufacturing Association, and the National Institute of Preservation of Cultural Properties. He has been a consultant for numerous state-funded historical preservation projects in Central New York.
He also has degrees in theatre from Carnegie-Mellon University and the Art Institute of Chicago, and has worked on sets, lighting and costumes for the Lyric Opera of Chicago and the St. Louis Municipal Opera, among other organizations.
Morigi has received numerous awards over his career, among them two Outstanding Teacher Awards from Syracuse University as well as that institution's Distinguished Professor Emeritus rank, the American Society of Interior Designers' Presidential Citation, and his students have received more than forty national and international student design awards from a wide range of industry and professional design organizations.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Frank Morigi Papers consist of material relating to Morigi's work for Norman R. DeHaan Associates in Chicago, and to his teaching career at Syracuse University.
DeHaan Associates material contains specifications, articles, clippings and photographs relating to education, hotel/restaurant, office space and retail projects, most of them in and around Chicago, Illinois where the firm was based. Projects include Hyde Park High School and the O'Hare International Tower hotel.
Syracuse University material includes awards won by the department and its students; exhibit invitations for the NY Eleven student organization; historic preservation projects in and around Syracuse including the well-known Octagon House; newsletters, handouts and other items related to the Design Department, both past and present; research projects, many of which were adapted for class projects for graduate and undergraduate students; and material relating to two seminars offered by the department.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by title or topic.
Subject and Genre Headings
Architects; Industrial Design; Morigi, Francis C.; Norman R. DeHaan Associates.; Syracuse University. -- College of Visual and Performing Arts.; Architecture -- Chicago Metropolitan Area.; Decoration and ornament, Architectural -- United States.; Historic buildings -- Conservation and restoration.; Hotels -- Design and construction.; Office layout.; Restaurants -- Design and construction.; Schools -- Design and construction.; Interior architecture -- United States.; Interior decoration -- United States.; Chicago (Ill.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Photographs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; College teachers.; Designers.; Interior decorators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Frank Morigi, 2011.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Resume / c.v. (Box 1)
- DeHaan Associates
  - Articles about
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Education projects
    - Elm Place Middle School, Highland Park, Illinois, 1971; specifications for furnishings and lockers (Box 1)
    - Governors State University, Park Forest South, Illinois, 1971; interim campus moveable equipment (Box 1)
    - Governors State University, Park Forest South, Illinois, working drawings (diazo prints), 28 sheets (Tube 1450)
    - Hyde Park High School, Chicago, Illinois, undated; published results of competition in which DeHaan Assoc. took second place (Box 1)
    - Sangamon State University, Springfield, Illinois, 1971; Phase B interim facilities interior partition systems (Box 1)
    - Mscellaneous printed items, articles, clippings, photographs (Box 1)
  - Hotel and restaurant projects
    - Arlington Park Tower, Arlington Heights, Illinois, 1973; specifications for fixed drapery and casement (Box 1)
    - Bronze Vail restaurant, 1968; Food Service Magazine article on the concept project; brochure with concept drawings (Box 1)
    - Cousins Club II supper club, Chicago, Illinois, 1970; specifications (Box 1)
    - Dayton's Bubbling Kettle, Fargo, North Dakota, 1972; specifications for cabinetry, room finish and carpet work; small set of blueprints (Box 1)
    - Don Roth restaurant, Chicago, Illinois, 1972; specifications (Box 1)
    - Frying Dutchman, 1968; Food Service Magazine article on the concept project (Box 1)
    - O'Hare International Tower hotel, Chicago, Illinois, 1972-1973; specifications for interior finishing of specific areas; specifications for carpeting; slides; two articles; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - O'Hare International Tower hotel, Chicago, Illinois, working drawings (diazo prints), 25 sheets (Tube 1453)
    - Taberna restaurant, 1970; specifications; Food Service Magazine article on (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous working drawings, 26 sheets (diazo prints) (Tube 1452)
  - Office planning
    - J & H International Corporation, 1970; specifications for carpeting (Box 2)
    - State National Bank, Evanston, Illinois, 1970; specifications for basement remodeling (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, undated (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous working drawings, 7 sheets (diazo prints) (Tube 1453)
  - Retail
    - Adler Shoe Store, Brooklyn, New York, 1970; specifications (Box 2)
    - Brass Boot shoe stores, 1970-1971; 1973; specifications for stores in Chicago, Milwaukee and New Orleans; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Brass Boot shoe store, 1970; 1973; specifications for Vernon Hills, Illinois, store; maintenance manual; printed publicity brochure (Box 3)
    - La Tinas store, New York, New York, 2 sets working drawings (diazo prints), 38 items (Tube 1450)
    - Morgan-Hayes Shoe Store, Dallas, Texas, 1970; specifications (Box 3)
    - Paddor's, Schaumburg, Illinois, 1971; specifications (Box 3)
    - Pompian Shop, Chicago, Illinois, 1970; specifications (Box 3)
    - Weyenberg Shoe Manufacturing / Brass Boot, 1973; specifications (Box 3)
    - Weyenberg Shoe Manufacturing / Brass Boot, working drawings for various locations (diazo prints), 54 sheets (Tube 1451)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, articles, clippings, photographs (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous working drawings, 33 sheets (diazo prints) (Tube 1452)
- Syracuse University
  - Awards
    - 1970s-1980s, awards won by SU Department of Design and/or its students; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1980s, 1990s, undated, awards won by students and/or by the SU Department of Design; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Exhibits
    - NY Eleven student exhibitions, 2002-2004; printed material (Box 4)
  - Historic preservation projects
    - Metropolitan School for the Arts, 1988; historic restoration and adaptive reuse of 1917 Masonic Temple as a school (Box 4)
    - Oakwood Cemetery, 1976; 1991,; undated; historic preservation and adaptive reuse study; printed material relating to history of the site (Box 4)
    - Octagon House (aka Wilcox Octagon House), 1987; historic restoration and adaptive reuse studies (Box 4)
    - Rescue Mission, 1998; project proposal for New Life Center (Box 4)
    - St. Camillus Health and Rehabilitation Center, 1997; interior design proposal (Box 5)
    - SA&K Building, 1984; renovation designs (Box 5)
    - Southside Preparatory Academy, 1985; relocation study (Box 5)
    - Spanish Action League, 1984; renovation grant proposal (Box 5)
    - Syracuse Visitors Center, 1986; redesign of Firehouse No. 1 as visitors' bureau (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, articles, clippings, photographs (Box 5)
  - Newsletters, handouts
    - Miscellaneous, 1980s; printed items relating to the Interior Design Program at SU (Box 5)
  - Program history
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1983; undated; correspondence, clippings, handwritten notes, other items relating to the history of the Interior Design Program at SU (Box 5)
  - Research
    - Circulation, 1985; "interior dialectics project" for DES447 (Box 5)
    - Free address office systems, 1990; "office of the future" project (Box 6)
    - Human office environment, 1986; Junior class sketch problem, project for DES348 (Box 6)
    - Human office environment, 1985; Senior class sketch problem, project for DES447 (Box 6)
    - Human office environment, 1986; description of project funded by grant from Haworth, Inc.; "The Future Workspace"; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Nursery environment forecast, 1992; student competition (Box 6)
    - Salesmanship, 1986; project for DES447 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous student projects, undated (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, 1985-1991; clippings, press releases, etc. (Box 7)
  - Seminars
    - 70 Years of Interior Design at Syracuse University, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Interior Design Education and the Future, 1975 (Box 7)